小席恩！来救她呀
Little Theon! Come and get her.
这是一封请柬……请我去君临
It's an invitation... to King's Landing.
你将代表我
You will represent my interests
出席他们那个会议
at this gathering as you see them.
扔下你和小指头在一起 太危险了
It's not safe leaving you with Littlefinger.
她是你的妹妹
She's your sister.
艾莉亚永远不会背叛亲人
Arya would never betray her family.
她会的 如果她觉得我会背叛琼恩
She would if she thought I was going to betray Jon.
有了这些脸 我就能变成别人
With the faces, I can become someone else.
我有点好奇做临冬城公爵夫人会是什么感觉
I wonder what it would feel like to be the Lady of Winterfell.
要知道这些 我唯一需要的……就是你的脸
All I'd need to find out... is your face.
丹妮莉丝会赢下这场战争
Daenerys will win this war.
你要是想让瑟曦下跪
If you want Cersei to bend the knee,
你大可自己去跟她说
you can ask her yourself.
她有更重要的请求
She has a more important request.
瑟曦不相信有死人军团
Cersei thinks the army of the dead is nothing
她认为那只是编出来的故事 如果我们能证明她是错的呢？
but a story. What if we prove her wrong?
把死人带去见她
Bring the dead to her.
走！
Go!
我们会消灭夜王和他的军队
We are going to destroy the Night King and his army.
谢谢你 女王陛下
Thank you, my queen.
最专业冰火字幕
诚意奉献
专注GOT剧集
翻译 点儿兔子
君临 King's Landing
翻译 熊岛莱安娜
红堡
Red Keep
翻译 叽拇啾
翻译 Ashara_C
龙石岛Dragonstone
翻译 耗斯特洛夫斯卡娅子
翻译 Taffy的北境雪诺
校对 托曼
校对 小猴会聪明
临冬城
Winterfell
校对 守誓的宝剑
校对 北落师门
联合出品
史诗图书 | 冰火中文维基 | 黑城堡奇幻微刊
Epic Books         ASOIAF.huiji.wiki          Heichengbao
最专业的华语冰火资料站：        冰与火之歌中文维基
http://asoiaf.huiji.wiki
后期 依依Eva
绝境长城 the Wall
推广 baozhenyuawabi
监制 北落师门
监制 临冬城的狮子
特别顾问 屈畅(ccxx)@史诗图书
东海望
Eastwatch
史诗图书  正统奇幻的圣殿
策划 衣柜军团
旧镇Oldtown
根据长篇小说
《冰与火之歌》 改编
原著  乔治·R·R·马丁
权力的游戏
衣柜字幕组
协力制作
史诗图书
Epic Books
ASOIAF.huiji.wiki
冰火中文维基
黑城堡
EPICASTLE
第七集
龙与狼
The Dragon and the Wolf
本字幕的制作目的是为了相关爱好者交流学习之用，
请在下载24小时之内删除。请勿用于任何商业用途。
灰虫子
无垢者的指挥官
- 油？ - 是沥青 大人
- Oil? - Pitch, my lord.
黑水河的波隆
爵士
- 有多少桶？ - 500桶 大人
- How many barrels? - 500, my lord.
再加500桶
Get 500 more.
遵命 大人
Yes, my lord.
詹姆·兰尼斯特
“弑君者”
直到现在 他们叫我“大人”都还挺受用的
I still enjoy it when they call me "my lord."
不过这种兴奋感早晚会消退
The thrill will fade.
前提是我们能活到那时候
If we live that long.
无屌军团
Men without cocks.
如果我被去了势
You wouldn't find me fighting in an army
肯定不会在军队里卖命打仗
if I had no cock.
都那样了还打仗 图个啥？
What's left to fight for?
金子？
Gold?
我这辈子都在和当兵的打交道
I spent my life around soldiers.
你以为他们会把金子花在哪里？
What do you think they spend that gold on?
家庭
Family.
没了鸡巴 你就不能给家庭花钱了
Not without a cock, you don't.
也许最终都是鸡巴说了算
Maybe it really is all cocks in the end.
但是 你弟弟却选择了和去势者为伍
Yet, your brother has chosen to side with the cockless.
是啊 他一直都是弱势者的英雄
Yes, he's always been a champion of the downtrodden.
看来我们也要被去势了
I think we're about to be the downtrodden.
弓箭手 准备！
Archers, stand tall!
守住那堵墙！
Cover that wall!
提利昂·兰尼斯特
女王之手
琼恩·雪诺
效忠丹妮莉丝的北境之王
戴佛斯·席渥斯
“洋葱骑士”
- 有多少人住在这里？ - 一百万左右
- How many people live here? - A million, give or take.
把全北境的人口算进去也没这么多
That's more people than the entire North crammed into that.
为什么会有人喜欢挤在这里？
Why would anyone want to live that way?
城里好找工作
There's more work in the city.
妓院更是无与伦比
And the brothels are far superior.
桑铎·克里冈
“猎狗”
她怎么没和他们一起？
Why isn't she with them?
陛下 恕我并不清楚缘由
I'm afraid I don't know, Your Grace.
还没人见到她
No one has seen her.
剩下的人呢？
And the rest of them?
瑟曦·兰尼斯特
铁王座上的女王
他们正在前往龙穴的路上
They're on their way to the Dragonpit now.
我们的弟弟也在？
Including our brother?
科本
被剥夺项链的学士 女王之手
是的 陛下
Yes, Your Grace.
如果有什么不对劲的
If anything goes wrong,
先宰了那银发婊子
kill the silver-haired bitch first,
然后是我们的弟弟 接着是那个自立为王的野种
then our brother, then the bastard who calls himself king.
劳勃·斯壮
格雷果·克里冈 “魔山”
剩下的人你按照什么顺序杀了都行
The rest of them you can kill in any order you see fit.
走吧 格雷果爵士
Come, Ser Gregor.
是时候会会我们的贵宾了
It's time for us to meet our guests.
他们为什么要修建这么一个地方？
Why did they build it?
巨龙分不清什么是属于它们的
Dragons don't understand the difference
什么不是
between what is theirs and what isn't.
土地 牲畜 孩子……
Land, livestock, children...
所以 由着它们在城市四周晃悠可能会很麻烦
Letting them roam free around a city was a problem.
我能想象得到这最后是个悲伤的笑话
I imagine it was a sad joke at the end.
整个竞技场最后只养了几头比狗还小的病恹恹的动物
An entire arena for a few sickly creatures smaller than dogs.
但最初 这里还住着“黑死神”贝勒里恩的时候
But in the beginning, when it was home to Balerion the Dread,
这一定是世上最危险的地方
it must have been the most dangerous place in the world.
也许它现在还是
Maybe it still is.
各位大人 欢迎欢迎
Welcome, my lords.
你们的朋友比你们先到一步
Your friends arrived before you did.
我奉命护送你们所有人到会场
I've been sent to escort you all to the meeting.
塔斯的布蕾妮
“美人”
弥桑黛
女王的翻译和顾问
乔拉·莫尔蒙
“大熊”
波德瑞克·派恩
布蕾妮的侍从
窘境下的意外之喜啊
A pleasant surprise in an unpleasant situation.
大人 我从没想过还能再次见到您
I never thought I'd see you again, my lord.
见到我仍然站在敌人那边 一如既往
Supporting the enemy, no less.
- 这也不能怪您 - 瑟曦可不这么觉得
- Hard to blame you. - Cersei will anyway.
我很高兴您还活着
I'm glad you're alive.
快跟上！
Come on!
等会再吸他的魔法大屌
You can suck his magic cock later.
里面是什么？
What's in there?
滚开
Fuck off.
我还以为你死了
I thought you were dead.
还没呢
Not yet.
你当时下手再狠点我就真死了
You came pretty close.
我只是在尽力保护她
I was only trying to protect her.
我们俩都在保护她
You and me both.
她还活着
She's alive.
艾莉亚
Arya.
- 她在哪？ - 临冬城
- Where? - Winterfell.
你在这儿 那谁来保护她？
Who's protecting her if you're here?
现在谁敢挡她的道
The only one that needs protecting
才需要考虑一下要怎么保护自己
is the one that gets in her way.
我肯定不去挡道
It won't be me.
现在走来的是……
Here we are...
黑水湾的英雄们
the heroes of Blackwater Bay.
真是奇怪的重逢地点
Strange place for a reunion.
是的 大人
It is, my lord.
我不觉得自己算什么大人了 波德瑞克
I don't think I'm anyone's lord anymore, Podrick.
还是把这头衔留给黑水河的波隆爵士吧
Save the titles for Ser Bronn of the Blackwater.
我敢肯定如果你的新女王坐上铁王座的话
I'm sure your new queen will be happy to restore yours
她会很乐意把你的头衔还给你
if she ends up on the throne.
你已经考虑过我们的新女王了？
You've been thinking about our new queen?
也许你得重新考虑一下该效忠谁了
Perhaps you've been reconsidering your allegiances.
瓦里斯
“八爪蜘蛛”
记住我的提议……
Remember my offer...
无论他们付给你多少酬劳 我都出双倍
whatever they're paying you, I'll pay double.
你现在到底能拿多少？
And that would be double what now, exactly?
不用你来担心我 我现在一切都好
Don't you worry about me. I'm doing all right.
- 我把自己照顾的很好 - 是吗？
- Looking after myself. - Are you?
你帮我组织了这次会谈
Helping me to arrange this meeting
还敢说是把自己照顾得很好？
wasn't exactly looking after yourself, was it?
你是让自己身处险境
You put yourself at risk.
我是让你身处险境 很不一样
I put yourself at risk. Important difference.
瑟曦女王悬赏一袋金龙要的是你的头 不是我的
It's your head Queen Cersei's offered a bag of gold for, it's not mine.
更何况现在多亏了我
Now, thanks to me,
两个叛徒的脑袋要进她的门
she's got two traitors' heads coming right through her door.
一旦听腻了他们臭嘴里的那些俏皮话
She can lop them both off as soon as she gets tired
她就会一刀砍掉他俩的头
of the clever words that pour out their pieholes.
这些都多亏了牛逼的黑水河的波隆爵士
All thanks to Ser Bronn of the fucking Blackwater.
如果那都不算是照顾好自己 我还真不知道什么算是了
If that's not looking after myself, I don't know what is.
再次见到你很高兴
It's good to see you again.
好吧 我也是
Yeah, you, too.
如果有任何人敢碰它 我先杀了你
Anyone touches it, I'll kill you first.
过来 波德
Come on, Pod.
趁这些大人物商谈大事的时候
Let's you and me go have a drink
咱们一起去喝一杯 嗯？
while the fancy folks talk, eh?
我离开了这个该死的城市
I left this shit city
是因为我不想死在这里
because I didn't want to die in it.
现在我会死在这个该死的城市吗？
Am I going to die in this shit city?
可能会
You might.
这都是你的主意
And this is all your idea.
好像每个坏点子背后都有兰尼斯特家的混蛋在出主意
Seems every bad idea has some Lannister cunt behind it.
同时还有克里冈家的混蛋在帮他们一手
And some Clegane cunt to help them see it through.
还记得我吗？
Remember me?
是啊 你还没忘
Yeah, you do.
你他妈的现在比我丑多了
You're even fucking uglier than I am now.
他们对你做了些什么？
What did they do to you?
这不重要了
Doesn't matter.
你不会就那么死去的 哥哥
That's not how it ends for you, brother.
你知道谁会来解决你
You know who's coming for you.
你一直都清楚
You've always known.
她在哪？
Where is she?
她马上就到
She'll be here soon.
没和你们一起来？
Didn't travel with you?
没有
No.
卓耿
女王的黑龙
攸伦·葛雷乔伊
铁群岛领主
丹妮莉丝·坦格利安
“风暴降生”  在龙石岛的女王
我们已经等候多时了
We've been here for some time.
抱歉
My apologies.
我们所有人都面临着一个前所未有的……
We are all facing a unique...
席恩！
Theon!
你姐姐在我手上
I have your sister.
如果你不立刻臣服于我
If you don't submit to me here, now...
我就杀了她
I'll kill her.
我认为我们应该先从大事谈起
I think we ought to begin with larger concerns.
那哪能轮到你在这废话？
Then why are you talking?
你是这里最小的
You're the smallest concern here.
你记得我们说过的侏儒的笑话吗？
Do you remember when we discussed dwarf jokes?
他说的根本不好笑
His wasn't even good.
他说完总要解释一下
He explained it at the end.
不要解释 解释就毁了
Never explain. It always ruins it.
我们铁群岛从来都不会
We don't even let your kind live
让你这种侏儒活下来 懂吗？
in the Iron Islands, you know?
你一生下来就会被杀死
We kill you at birth.
这是对你父母的一种仁慈
An act of mercy for the parents.
或许你应该坐下
Perhaps you ought to sit down.
为什么
Why?
坐下 要么离开
Sit down or leave.
我们是一群互相看不顺眼的人
We are a group of people who do not like one another,
最近这几场战争已经说明了这一点
as this recent demonstration has shown.
我们都因彼此而经受过苦难
We have suffered at each other's hands.
也因互相争斗而失去挚爱
We have lost people we love at each other's hands.
如果我们只想继续缠斗不休
If all we wanted was more of the same,
聚集此地也就没有了意义
there would be no need for this gathering.
我们完全可以直接兵戈相见
We are entirely capable of waging war against each other
而不必当面会见
without meeting face-to-face.
那你认为我们应该把争议放在一边
So instead, we should settle our differences
然后和谐地生活在一起？
and live together in harmony for the rest of our days?
谁都知道那是不可能的
We all know that will never happen.
那我们到底为何而来
Then why are we here?
现在根本还谈不上和谐共存
This isn't about living in harmony.
只是为了生存下去
It's just about living.
我们所有人都面临着同样的威胁
The same thing is coming for all of us.
一个根本不可能谈判的将军
A general you can't negotiate with.
带领着一支能将战场上每一具尸体都化为己用的军队
An army that doesn't leave corpses behind on the battlefield.
提利昂大人告诉我这城里有一百万人口
Lord Tyrion tells me a million people live in this city.
他们也将会变成亡者大军里的百万雄兵
They're about to become a million more soldiers in the Army of the Dead.
我猜大多数人会觉得那样活得更好
I imagine for most of them it would be an improvement.
这是很严肃的问题
This is serious.
如果不是事态紧急 我也不会来到这里
I wouldn't be here if it weren't.
这种问题根本无法严肃
I don't think it's serious at all.
只不过是又一个无趣的笑话
I think it's another bad joke.
如果我的弟弟詹姆没有说错的话
If my brother Jaime has informed me correctly,
你是来请求休战的
you're asking me for a truce.
是的 就是这样
Yes. That's all.
就这样而已？
That's all?
让我的军队撤退待命
Pull back my armies and stand down
而你骑着你的怪物继续大肆屠杀
while you go on your monster hunt.
或者继续巩固势力 扩大领土
Or while you solidify and expand your position.
如果我下令撤军 你会继续采取哪条路线？
Hard for me to know which it is with my armies pulled back
直到你率领比现在多三倍的军队回到我的都城 我才能知道吧
until you return and march on my capital with four times the men.
北方的威胁平息之前 你的都城会安然无恙
Your capital will be safe until the northern threat is dealt with.
我向你保证
You have my word.
一个准篡位者的保证
The word of a would-be usurper.
过去五十年的恩怨纠葛
There is no conversation
不会因一场谈话而抹去
that will erase the last 50 years.
我们有东西想给你看看
We have something to show you.
我们可以烧死他们
We can destroy them by burning them.
也可以用龙晶杀死他们
And we can destroy them with dragonglass.
如果这场战争我们输了
If we don't win this fight,
那世界上所有人都会落得如此下场
then that is the fate of every person in the world.
只有这场战争才有意义
There is only one war that matters...
生存之战
the Great War.
就在眼下
And it is here.
如果不是亲眼见到他们 我也无法相信
I didn't believe it until I saw them.
我全都看到了
I saw them all.
有多少？
How many?
十万大军 最少来说
A hundred thousand, at least.
他们会水吗
Can they swim?
不会
No.
很好
Good.
我这就带着铁舰队返回铁群岛
I'm taking the Iron Fleet back to the Iron Islands.
你说什么？
What are you talking about?
我曾周游世界
I've been around the world.
见识无数 包括很多你无法想象的东西
I've seen everything, things you couldn't imagine,
但这是……
and this...
这是唯一一次吓到我的
this is the only thing I've ever seen that terrifies me.
我要回到我的岛上去
I'm going back to my island.
你也应该回你的地盘
You should go back to yours.
当凛冬结束
When winter's over,
我们就会是唯一幸存的活人
we'll be the only ones left alive.
他害怕是对的
He's right to be afraid.
像懦夫一样逃跑也没错
And a coward to run.
如果这些东西朝我们袭来
If those things come for us,
没有一个王国能够幸存
there will be no kingdoms to rule.
我们承受的苦难将没有意义
Everything we suffered will have been for nothing.
我们失去的一切也将没有意义
Everything we lost will have been for nothing.
铁王座接受你的休战请求
The crown accepts your truce.
直到消灭亡者大军 因为他们才是真正的敌人
Until the dead are defeated, they are the true enemy.
作为回报 北境之王要延长休战时间
In return, the King in the North will extend this truce.
他必须留在他的北境
He will remain in the North where he belongs.
他不能起兵与兰尼斯特为敌
He will not take up arms against the Lannisters.
他也不能选择任何一边
He will not choose sides.
只包括北境之王？
Just the King in the North?
不包括我？
Not me?
我永远不会向你提这种要求
I would never ask it of you.
你也永远不会同意
You would never agree to it.
如果你同意 我反而更加不信任你
And if you did, I would trust you even less than I do now.
我只想要奈德·史塔克之子的承诺
I ask it only of Ned Stark's son.
我知道他的儿子会信守承诺
I know Ned Stark's son will be true to his word.
我言出必行
I am true to my word.
起码竭尽全力
Or I try to be.
但正因如此 我不能答应你
That is why I cannot give you what you ask.
我不能同时效忠两个女王
I cannot serve two queens.
我已经宣誓效忠
And I have already pledged myself
坦格利安家族的丹妮莉丝女王
to Queen Daenerys of House Targaryen.
那就没什么好谈的了
Then there is nothing left to discuss.
亡者大军会先到达北境 好好享受这场战争吧
The dead will come north first. Enjoy dealing with them.
我们会处理你们变成的那些东西
We will deal with whatever is left of you.
詹姆爵士
Ser Jaime.
很高兴见到你
It's been good to see you.
我猜下次就要兵戎相见了
I imagine the next time will be across a battlefield.
刚才我们都看到了
We both saw what just happened.
我们都看到了那个……东西
We both saw that... thing.
是的 我一点也不想再见到那些东西
Yes, and I'm not looking forward to seeing more of them.
但是我忠于瑟曦女王
But I'm loyal to the queen,
你忠于珊莎和她的蠢哥哥
and you're loyal to Sansa and her dolt brother.
去他妈的忠诚！
Oh, fuck loyalty!
去他妈的忠诚？
Fuck loyalty?
这已经无关家族 荣誉或者誓言
This goes beyond houses and honor and oaths.
去和女王谈谈
Talk to the queen.
还能谈什么？
And tell her what?
你刚才没那么做就好了
I wish you hadn't done that.
我很感激你的忠诚
I'm grateful for your loyalty,
但我的龙为了这次谈判而死
but my dragon died so that we could be here.
如果这场谈判以失败收场
If it's all for nothing,
那它就白白牺牲了
then he died for nothing.
我知道！
I know!
我很高兴你向我们的女王屈膝称臣
I'm pleased you bent the knee to our queen.
就像之前我劝你的那样
I would have advised it, had you asked.
但是你有没有考虑过
But have you ever considered
学习一下偶尔撒个谎？
learning how to lie every now and then?
哪怕就一次？
Just a bit?
我绝不能违背誓言
I'm not going to swear an oath I can't uphold.
如果你想告诉我
Talk about my father if you want,
我父亲就是因此而死的 那就说吧
tell me that's the attitude that got him killed.
但是太多的虚假承诺
But when enough people make false promises,
就使得承诺没有了任何意义
words stop meaning anything.
世间将没有真相 只有更精致的谎言
Then there are no more answers, only better and better lies.
谎言绝对无益于这场战争
And lies won't help us in this fight.
这确实是个问题
That is indeed a problem.
但现在更严重的问题是我们完了
The more immediate problem is that we're fucked.
有没有任何办法
Any ideas as to how we might
来扭转局面？
change that state of affairs?
只有一个方法
Only one.
你们都待在这
Everyone stays here,
我去和我的姐姐谈谈
and I go and talk to my sister.
我经历这一切前来 可不是让我的首相去送死
I didn't come all this way to have my Hand murdered.
我也不想被瑟曦杀掉
I don't want Cersei to murder me either.
不然当时我就乖乖待在牢房里了 省得这些麻烦
I could have stayed in my cell and saved a great deal of trouble.
责任在我
I did this.
- 该由我去 - 她一定会杀了你
- I should go. - She'll definitely murder you.
由我独自去见姐姐
I go see my sister alone.
不然我们将无功而返
Or we all go home
原地踏步 一无所获
and we're right back where we started.
- 你和她谈过了？ - 对 她还把我赶了出来
- You spoke with her? - At her until she kicked me out.
瑟曦觉得我是个傻瓜 还相信你
She thinks I was an idiot to trust you.
实际上 似乎不少人也这么想
A lot of people seem to think that, actually.
我将要步入的这个房间里
I'm about to step into a room
有世上最残忍的女人
with the most murderous woman in the world
她还两次试图杀我 而这一切我都清清楚楚
who's already tried to kill me twice, that I know of.
谁才是傻瓜？
Who's an idiot?
我们该道别了
I suppose we should say goodbye,
两个傻瓜之间的道别
one idiot to another.
意料之中呀
I shouldn't be surprised, I suppose.
她是你喜欢的那类女人……
She's your kind of woman...
自高自大的外国婊子
a foreign whore who doesn't know her place.
不能绑架 毒打或者胁迫 一个你不能拿她如何的外国婊子
A foreign whore you can't abduct, beat, or intimidate.
对你来说挺不容易对付的吧
That must be difficult for you.
所以你把她和她的北境男宠弄到这儿来
So you bring her here with her pet Northerner,
- 还设法说服了那家伙向她效忠 - 我之前并不知道这件事
- whom you've convinced to bow down before her. - I didn't know about that.
可现在你把他俩弄到一块儿了 目标一致
And now you've got them both working towards the same goal,
而且是你这一生为之努力的目标……
the goal you've worked towards your entire life...
- 瑟曦 我之前并不知道 - ……摧毁整个家族
- Cersei, I didn't know. - ...the destruction of this family.
我来是为了避免那一切发生
I am the one preventing that from happening.
丹妮莉丝最开始不可能来讨论或谈判
Daenerys didn't want to debate and negotiate.
也不可能来跟你对话
She didn't want to bring you words.
她只想要带来血与火
She wanted to bring you fire and blood
直到我向她谏言
until I advised her otherwise.
我并不想摧毁我们的家族
I don't want to destroy our family.
从未如此
I never have.
你杀了父亲
You killed our father.
我因从未犯过的罪
After he sentenced me to death
被他判了死刑 没错 我的确杀了他
for a crime I didn't commit, yes, I killed him.
要恨我就恨我吧
Hate me for it if you want.
且不说他是我父亲 也不论他对我做的那些
I hate myself for it in spite of what he was,
我是杀了他 也依然痛恨我自己
in spite of what he did to me.
噢 可怜的小家伙
Oh, poor little man.
父亲对你不好
Your papa was mean to you.
可当你射出那支弩箭时 你知道自己在做什么吗？
Do you have any idea what you did when you fired that crossbow?
你陷我们于危险之中
You left us open.
你把我们暴露给了贪婪的敌人
You laid us bare for the vultures,
而敌人害得我们一家分离
and the vultures came and tore us apart.
或许并不是你害死了乔佛里
You may not have killed Joffrey,
但是你害死了弥赛菈 是你害死了托曼
but you killed Myrcella, you killed Tommen.
如果父亲还在世 没人敢动他们一下
No one would've touched them if Father was here.
- 没人胆敢…… - 万分抱歉
- No one would have dared... - I have never been more sorry about anything.
我不想听到这话 更不想从你口中听到
I will not hear it, not from you.
我不想听！
I will not hear it!
好吧
All right.
你爱你的家庭
You love your family,
而我毁了这一切
and I have destroyed it.
我永远都是个威胁
I will always be a threat.
那就了结我吧
So put an end to me.
如果不是因为我 母亲还在世
If it weren't for me, you'd have a mother.
如果不是因为我 父亲也还活着
If it weren't for me, you'd have a father.
如果不是因为我
If it weren't for me,
你还会拥有一双漂亮的儿女
you'd have two beautiful children.
我也早已不止一次
I've thought about killing you
想过要杀了你
more times than I can count.
动手！ 下命令吧
Do it! Say the word.
你不曾知道 孩子们的事情 我非常抱歉
I am more sorry about the children than you could ever know.
- 我不…… - 无所谓 但我深爱他们
- I will not... - I don't care. I loved them.
你心里明白
You know I did.
你心里还有些感情 就会明白我所说的
You know it in your heart if there's anything left of it.
无关紧要
It doesn't matter.
你的爱无关紧要 感受也无关紧要
Your love doesn't matter. Your feelings don't matter.
我不关心原因 也不在乎你做了什么
I don't care why you did what you did.
我只在意我们付出了什么
I only care what it cost us.
我们付出了未来
It cost us our future.
如果真的没有了未来 那我们为何在这儿？
If there's no future, then why are we here?
你又为何允许我来见你？
Why did you allow me to come?
绝不是为了帮助敌人联手对付我
Not to help my enemies collaborate in my destruction.
当然不是 也不是你想要的那样
Yes, no, not what you hoped for,
但你一定有非要不可的东西
but you must have hoped for something.
那你又想要什么？
What did you hope for?
- 让琼恩·雪诺效忠你的女王？ - 嗯 不是这样的方式
- To make Jon Snow submit to your queen? - Mm, not like this.
可实际上 你想要所有人都臣服她
But eventually, you want everyone to bend the knee to her.
- 没错 - 为什么？
- Yes. - Why?
我相信
Because I think
她能让世界变好
she will make the world a better place.
可你说她想毁了君临城
You said she'd destroy King's Landing.
她了解自己
She knows herself.
她所选的谋臣
She chose an advisor
会忠言进谏而不是一味顺从
who would check her worst impulses instead of feeding them.
这是她和你的不同
That's the difference between you.
我不关心忠言进谏
I don't care about checking my worst impulses.
也不在乎让世界更美好
I don't care about making the world a better place.
去它的世界
Hang the world.
你来的那东西
That thing you dragged here,
我知道那是什么 也明白那意味着什么
I know what it is, I know what it means.
当那家伙朝我冲来时 我并没有在想这个世界
And when it came at me, I didn't think about the world.
压根没有
Not at all.
当他张开嘴
As soon as it opened its mouth,
世界消失了
the world disappeared for me,
消失在他黑乎乎的喉咙里
right down its black throat.
我所能想到的 就是把那口咬得咯咯作响的白牙
All I could think about was keeping those gnashing teeth
从我重视的人们面前弄走
away from the ones who matter most,
从我的家族面前弄走
away from my family.
攸伦·葛雷乔伊或许是对的
Maybe Euron Greyjoy had the right idea.
登上船 带走重要的人们……
Get on a boat, take those who matter...
你怀孕了
You're pregnant.
应该不会有人比我更难受了吧
No one is less happy about this than I am.
我理解
I know.
我尊重你的选择
I respect what you did.
尽管我不希望你那么做 但我尊重你所做的
Wish you hadn't done it, but I respect it.
这个地方是我的家族末日的开端
This place was the beginning of the end for my family.
龙并不是奴隶
A dragon is not a slave.
龙令人生惧
They were terrifying.
望而生畏
Extraordinary.
龙让人们惊叹 敬畏
They filled people with wonder and awe,
可我们却把龙锁在这儿
and we locked them in here.
龙日渐衰微
They wasted away.
变得越来越弱小
They grew small.
我们家族也是如此
And we grew small as well.
没有龙 我们不再独一无二
We weren't extraordinary without them.
和芸芸众生没有区别
We were just like everyone else.
但你并不是普通人
You're not like everyone else.
你的家族也并没有走向终结
And your family hasn't seen its end.
你还在这儿
You're still here.
可我无法生育
I can't have children.
谁告诉你的？
Who told you that?
害死了我丈夫的女巫
The witch who murdered my husband.
难道你没有想过
Has it occurred to you she might not have been
那个女巫可能故意骗你？
a reliable source of information?
你从一开始就是对的
You were right from the beginning.
我早就该相信你 事情就不会发展成这样了
If I had trusted you, everything would be different.
那现在呢？
So, what now?
长城以北的所见让我触目惊心
I can't forget what I saw north of the Wall.
当我率军北上
And I can't pretend that Cersei
不可能假装以为瑟曦会对这大半个王国无所作为
won't take back half the country the moment I march north.
提利昂的那句话或许是对的
It appears Tyrion's assessment was correct.
我们完了
We're fucked.
我不会按兵不动
My armies will not stand down.
也不会下令撤回君临
I will not pull them back to the capital.
我将命令他们北进 在大战中协助你们
I will march them north to fight alongside you in the Great War.
黑暗正冲着我们所有人而来
The darkness is coming for us all.
我们要携手御敌
We'll face it together.
当这场大战结束
And when the Great War is over,
希望你们还记得 我曾选择帮助你们
perhaps you'll remember I chose to help
即便你们当中没有人给予我承诺或保证
with no promises or assurances from any of you.
但愿你们别忘了
I expect not.
召集封臣
Call our banners.
所有封臣
All of them.
让渡鸦在这种暴风雪中飞翔可不容易
It's not easy for ravens to fly in these storms.
也许琼恩本想早些送信
Perhaps Jon tried to send word earlier.
珊莎·史塔克
临冬城公爵夫人
不 他就是这样
No, this is the way he is,
一直都是这样
the way he's always been.
他从不过问我的意见 这次又怎么会例外？
He never asked for my opinion. Why would he start now?
难以置信 他没和你商量就放弃了北境的王位
I can't believe he'd surrender the Northern crown without consulting you.
培提尔·贝里席
“小指头”
这是他的笔迹 他的签名
This is his writing, his signature.
他宣誓为丹妮莉丝·坦格利安而战
He pledged to fight for Daenerys Targaryen.
他已经屈膝称臣了
He's bent the knee.
传言说
I've heard gossip
龙女王美貌非凡
that the Dragon Queen is quite beautiful.
这有什么关系？
What does that have to do with anything?
琼恩年轻 未婚
Jon is young and unmarried.
丹妮莉丝年轻 独身
Daenerys is young and unmarried.
你觉得他想娶她？
You think he wants to marry her?
结盟是明智的选择
An alliance makes sense.
他们并肩作战 就会难以被打败
Together, they'd be difficult to defeat.
他曾被拥为北境之王
He was named King in the North.
也可以被废黜
He can be unnamed.
就算我同意 艾莉亚也绝不会同意
Even if I wanted to, Arya would never go along.
她很爱琼恩 比爱我要多得多
She always loved Jon far more than she ever loved me,
她会杀掉任何背叛家族之人
and she'd kill anyone who betrayed her family.
你也是她家族的一员
You are family, too.
艾莉亚真的会对亲姐姐痛下杀手吗？
Would Arya really murder her own sister?
你知道她现在的身份吗？
Do you know what she is now?
你知道无面者都是什么人吗？
Do you know what the Faceless Men are?
有所耳闻
Only by reputation.
我知道他们信奉死神
They worship the God of Death, I believe.
我从不信那些所谓的神
I never trust godly men.
他们是杀手
They're killers.
而艾莉亚是其中一员
And Arya was one of them.
你认为她之后要干吗？
What do you think she's after?
她是你妹妹
She's your sister.
你比我了解她多了
You know her far better than I ever could.
有时候 我试图猜测别人的动机时
Sometimes when I try to understand a person's motives,
就玩一个小游戏
I play a little game.
先假设最坏的情况
I assume the worst.
当他们说这些话 做这些事的时候
What's the worst reason they could possibly have
他们最可怕的动机可能是什么？
for saying what they say and doing what they do?
然后我问自己
Then I ask myself,
这个动机
How well does that reason explain
能否合理解释他们的言行？
what they say and what they do?
所以 告诉我……
So, tell me...
她想要的最可怕的东西是什么？
what's the worst thing she could want?
她想要我死
She could want me dead
因为她觉得我出卖了家族
because she thinks I wronged my family.
她为什么来临冬城？
Why did she come to Winterfell?
为了杀我
To kill me
以报我嫁给敌人 背叛家族之仇
for marrying our enemies and betraying my family.
她为什么找出瑟曦强迫你写的那封信？
Why did she unearth the letter Cersei made you write?
为了有证据证实我背叛了家族
To provide proof of my betrayals.
好让她名正言顺地杀了我
To provide justification after she murders me.
那在她杀了你之后
And after she murders you,
她会成为什么？
what does she become?
临冬城公爵夫人
Lady of Winterfell.
如果让多斯拉克骑兵在国王大道上疾行
If we have the Dothraki ride hard on the kingsroad,
两周之内就能到达临冬城
they'll arrive at Winterfell within the fortnight.
那无垢者呢？
And the Unsullied?
他们可以航行至白港
We can sail with them to White Harbor,
与多斯拉克骑兵在国王大道上会合 在这个位置
meet the Dothraki here on the kingsroad,
然后一同前往临冬城
then ride together to Winterfell.
也许您应该乘龙飞去临冬城 陛下
Perhaps you should fly to Winterfell, Your Grace.
您在北境树敌不少
You have many enemies in the North.
成千人因反抗您父亲而战死
Thousands fell fighting your father.
只要一个手持十字弓的愤怒之人
All it takes is one angry man with a crossbow.
在国王大道上看见您的银发
He'll see your silver hair on the kingsroad
精准的一箭就可让他青史留名
and know that one well-placed bolt will make him a hero.
成为杀死征服者的人
The man who killed the conqueror.
请您自己定夺 陛下
It's your decision, Your Grace.
但如果我们要在这场战争中结盟
But if we're going to be allies in this war,
让北境人亲眼目睹这一刻相当重要
it's important for the Northerners to see us as allies.
席恩·葛雷乔伊
如果我们共同航行至白港
If we sail to White Harbor together,
就能很好地说明问题
I think it sends a better message.
我不是来征服北境的
I've not come to conquer the North.
我是来拯救北境的
I'm coming to save the North.
我们共同航行
We sail together.
琼恩
Jon.
我能和你说两句话吗？
Can I speak with you?
好吧
All right.
你在君临的所作所为
What you did in King's Landing,
你说的话……
what you said...
你本可以欺骗瑟曦
you could've lied to Cersei
说你没向丹妮莉丝屈膝称臣
about bending the knee to Daenerys.
你冒着全盘皆输的风险只为告诉敌人真相
You risked everything to tell an enemy the truth.
我们是去讲和的
We went down there to make peace.
我觉得坦诚相待很重要
And it seems to me we need to be honest with each other
如果我们要并肩作战的话
if we're going to fight together.
你总知道怎么做才对
You've always known what was right.
即使在我们都年少无知的时候
Even when we were all young and stupid,
你也总是知道
you always knew.
你走的每一步……
Every step you take...
都是正确的
it's always the right step.
不是这样
It's not.
从旁观者的角度来看可能如此
It may seem that way from the outside,
但我跟你保证 事实不是这样
but I promise you, it's not true.
我做了很多让我后悔的事
I've done plenty of things that I regret.
跟我比起来那也不算什么
Not compared to me, you haven't.
是
No.
和你比确实不算什么
Not compared to you.
我一直都想做正确的事
I always wanted to do the right thing.
做个好人
Be the right kind of person.
但我一直不懂该怎么做
But I never knew what that meant.
就好像……
It always seemed like there's...
一直以来我都面临着一个艰难的抉择
like there was an impossible choice I had to make.
是史塔克还是葛雷乔伊
Stark or Greyjoy.
对你来说 我们的父亲比你生父更像一个真正的父亲
Our father was more of a father to you than yours ever was.
- 确实 - 而你背叛了他
- He was. - And you betrayed him.
在他死后背叛了他的魂灵
Betrayed his memory.
是的
I did.
但你从未失去他
But you never lost him.
他是你的一部分
He's a part of you.
就像他也是我的一部分……
Just like he's a part of me.
但我做过的事……
But the things I've done...
我没有资格原谅你的全部行径
It's not my place to forgive you for all of it.
但就我个人而言
But what I can forgive,
我原谅你
I do.
你不必做出选择
You don't need to choose.
你姓葛雷乔伊……
You're a Greyjoy...
也是史塔克家族的成员
and you're a Stark.
在我还是拉姆斯的囚徒时
When I was Ramsay's prisoner,
亚拉试图救我
Yara tried to save me.
只有她一个
She's the only one
试过救我
who tried to save me.
她现在需要我
She needs me now.
那你现在还在这磨叽什么？
So, why are you still talking to me?
装货
Load up.
小伙子们 加把劲儿
Load up, lads. Go on.
就要涨潮了
Tide's coming in.
哈拉吉
追随亚拉的船长
我们都曾自愿跟随亚拉
All of us chose to follow Yara.
为了她离开铁群岛
We left the Iron Islands for Yara.
她绝对不会抛弃我们中的任何一个人
She would never leave one of us behind.
我们也不能抛弃她
We're not leaving her behind.
你姐死了
Your sister's dead.
- 她没死 - 就是死了
- She's not dead. - She's dead.
就算攸伦现在还没割她喉 她也死路一条
Even if Euron hasn't cut her throat yet, she's dead.
- 她是我们的女王 - 她是你姐 而你抛下她等死
- She's our queen. - She's your sister, and you left her to die.
是
I did.
我从我叔叔手底下逃跑了
I ran from my uncle.
我那时是个懦夫
I was a coward.
所以 我们他妈的为什么要听你的？
So, why in fuck's name should we listen to you?
他们说尸鬼不会游泳
They say the dead can't swim.
我们要向东航行
We're going to sail east,
找一个漂亮 安静的岛
find a nice, quiet island,
杀掉那儿的人 抢走他们的妻子
kill all the men, and take their wives for ourselves.
- 我们不再做这种事了 - 谁说的？
- We're done with all that. - Who says we are?
亚拉说的 她宣誓了
Yara did. She made a pledge.
我们要去找她
We're going to find her,
然后救她出来
and we're going to set her free.
你还是快跑吧 小席恩
Run away, little Theon.
逃跑才是你最擅长的本领
It's what you do best.
让他闭嘴
He needs to shut his mouth.
嘿！
Hey!
漂亮！
Oh, yes!
这才像话
That's more like it.
待着别动……
Stay down...
不然我就弄死你！
or I'll kill you!
我说了待着别动！不然我就弄死你！
I said stay down or I'll kill you!
这不是为了我
Not for me.
是为了亚拉！
For Yara!
亚拉！
Yara!
把我妹妹带到大厅去
Have my sister brought to the Great Hall.
布兰·史塔克
绿先知
沃肯
临冬城的学士
约恩·罗伊斯
“青铜” 符石城伯爵
艾莉亚·史塔克
你真的要这样做？
Are you sure you want to do this?
我并不愿意 但家族荣誉令我不得不如此
It's not what I want. It's what honor demands.
家族荣誉要求你做什么了？
And what does honor demand?
要求我守护家人 不让他们为奸人所害
That I defend my family from those who would harm us.
要求我守护北境 不让它为叛徒所染指
That I defend the North from those who would betray us.
那好
All right, then.
动手吧
Get on with it.
你被控犯有谋杀罪
You stand accused of murder.
你被控犯有叛国罪
You stand accused of treason.
对此你作何解释……
How do you answer these charges...
贝里席大人？
Lord Baelish?
我姐姐问你话呢
My sister asked you a question.
珊莎小姐 请原谅……
Lady Sansa, forgive me...
我有些不明白
I'm a bit confused.
你有什么不明白的呢？
Which charges confuse you?
先说说最简单的一桩吧……
Let's start with the simplest one...
你杀害了我们的阿姨 莱莎·艾林
you murdered our aunt, Lysa Arryn.
你将她推下月门 眼看着她摔下去
You pushed her through the Moon Door and watched her fall.
你不承认吗？
Do you deny it?
我是为了保护您才那样做的
I did it to protect you.
你是为了夺取谷地的统治权才那样做的
You did it to take power in the Vale.
在那之前 你还密谋杀害琼恩·艾林
Earlier, you conspired to murder Jon Arryn.
你给了莱莎里斯之泪 让她毒死他
You gave Lysa Tears of Lys to poison him.
你要抵赖吗？
Do you deny it?
不管您阿姨都告诉了您些什么……
Whatever your aunt might have told you...
她的心智有问题啊
she was a troubled woman.
她总觉得到处都有敌人
She imagined enemies everywhere.
你让莱莎阿姨写信给我们的父母
You had Aunt Lysa send a letter to our parents
告诉他们杀害琼恩·艾林的是兰尼斯特家族
telling them it was the Lannisters who murdered Jon Arryn
但实际上 是你杀的
when, really, it was you.
史塔克家族和兰尼斯特家族之间的冲突
The conflict between the Starks and the Lannisters,
是你挑起的
it was you who started it.
还不承认吗？
Do you deny it?
我从来没听说过有这封信
I know of no such letter.
你和瑟曦·兰尼斯特
You conspired with Cersei Lannister
还有乔佛里·拜拉席恩沆瀣一气 背叛我们的父亲奈德·史塔克
and Joffrey Baratheon to betray our father, Ned Stark.
因为你的暗算 他被关进地牢
Thanks to your treachery, he was imprisoned
后被处死 都因为这捏造的叛国罪
and later executed on false charges of treason.
- 还要抵赖吗？ - 我否认！
- Do you deny it? - I deny it!
到底发生了什么你们谁都没有看到
None of you were there to see what happened.
谁都不知道真相
None of you knows the truth.
你把匕首架在他喉咙上
You held a knife to his throat.
还说 “我警告过您不要信任我”
You said, "I did warn you not the trust me."
你告诉我们的母亲 说这把匕首是提利昂·兰尼斯特的
You told our mother this knife belonged to Tyrion Lannister.
那也是你撒的谎之一
But that was another one of your lies.
匕首是你的
It was yours.
珊莎小姐 您还是个孩子的时候我们就认识了
Lady Sansa, I have known you since you were a girl.
- 我保护过您啊 - 保护过我？
- I've protected you. - Protected me?
把我卖给波顿家族来保护我？
By selling me to the Boltons?
如果您允许我单独跟您谈谈
If we could speak alone,
我就能解释清楚一切
I can explain everything.
当我试图弄清某人的企图的时候
Sometimes when I'm trying to understand a person's motives,
我会玩一个小游戏
I play a little game.
假设他有最可怕的目的
I assume the worst.
让我和妹妹反目
What's the worst reason you have
背后最可怕的目的是什么呢？
for turning me against my sister?
这不就是你的把戏吗？
That's what you do, isn't it?
这就是你一直在玩的手段……
That's what you've always done...
挑拨家族内乱
turn family against family,
姐妹反目
turn sister against sister.
这就是你对我们的母亲和莱莎阿姨所做的
That's what you did to our mother and Aunt Lysa,
还准备对我们故伎重演
and that's what you tried to do to us.
珊莎 求求你
Sansa, please.
确实 我学起谋略来很慢
I'm a slow learner, it's true.
但我还是学到了
But I learn.
给我一个为自己辩护的机会吧
Give me a chance to defend myself.
那是我应得的
I deserve that.
我可是谷地守护者
I am Lord Protector of the Vale
我命令你们护送我安全回到鹰巢城
and I command you to escort me safely back to the Eyrie.
我可不同意
I think not.
珊莎 我恳求你！
Sansa, I beg you!
我从小就爱慕你的母亲
I loved your mother since the time I was a boy.
但你还是背叛了她
And yet, you betrayed her.
我爱你
I loved you.
比任何人都爱
More than anyone.
但你还是背叛了我
And yet, you betrayed me.
你带我回到临冬城的时候
When you brought me back to Winterfell,
告诉我世上没有正义可言
you told me there's no justice in the world,
除非我们去亲手夺取
not unless we make it.
感谢你的诸多教导 贝里席大人
Thank you for all your many lessons, Lord Baelish.
我永远不会忘记
I will never forget them.
珊莎！
Sansa!
我……
I...
我们在君临的部队
Our men in King's Landing
三天后将会向北进发
will march north in three days' time.
但搜集部队所需的物资
It'll take us a fortnight
需要两周时间啊
just to gather supplies for the train.
我们拿不出两周时间
We don't have a fortnight.
北境要是陷落 我们也会灭亡 给你三天时间
If the North falls, we fall. Three days.
西境剩余的军队
The remaining forces in the Westerlands
将会取道河间大道以东
will take the river road east.
我们在哈罗威伯爵城下会师
We'll meet at Lord Harroway's Town
然后一起向临冬城进军
and march together to Winterfell.
詹姆爵士
Ser Jaime.
陛下
Your Grace.
诸位 我需要和我弟弟单独说几句话
My lords, I need a moment with my brother.
那我们告退了 陛下
Your Grace.
- 你在干什么？ - 准备远征北方
- What are you doing? - Preparing the expedition north.
远征北方？
Expedition north?
我就知道你是家族里最蠢的那个
I always knew you were the stupidest Lannister.
史塔克家族和坦格利安家族已经结盟对抗起我们了
The Starks and Targaryens have united against us,
你居然还想跟他们并肩作战？
and you want to fight alongside them?
你是叛徒还是傻子？
Are you a traitor or an idiot?
你发过誓要一起打击我们共同的敌人的……
You pledged our forces to fight our common enemy...
只要能保证家族的延续
I'll say whatever I need to say
该说的我都会说
to ensure the survival of our house.
你以为我会信任杀害了父亲的人吗？
You expect me to trust the man who murdered our father?
你以为我会命令我们的部队和异邦渣滓一起
You expect me to command our troops to fight beside foreign scum,
为龙女王作战吗？
to fight for the Dragon Queen?
你自己也亲眼看见了
You saw it with your own eyes.
那个死人试图要杀我们
You saw a dead man trying to kill us.
我看见它烧成了灰
I saw it burn.
如果龙不能消灭他们
If dragons can't stop them,
如果多斯拉克人 无垢者还有北境人都不能消灭他们
if Dothraki and Unsullied and Northmen can't stop them,
我们的军队又能做什么呢？
how will our armies make a difference?
这不是贵族与贵族间的战争
This isn't about noble houses,
这是活人和死尸间的战争！
this is about the living and the dead!
而我打算待在活人中间
And I intend to stay amongst the living.
就让那个史塔克小子和他的新女王去保卫北境吧
Let the Stark boy and his new queen defend the North.
我们待在我们的老地方
We stay here where we've always been.
我发过誓
I made a promise.
我们的孩子将会统治维斯特洛
Our child will rule Westeros.
要是尸鬼南下 我们的孩子就永远不可能出生了
Our child will never be born if the dead come south.
这些怪物确实存在
The monsters are real.
异鬼
The white walkers,
龙 多斯拉克哮吼武士
the dragons, the Dothraki screamers...
我们小时候听的那些吓唬人的故事 全都是真的
all the frightening stories we heard when we were young, they're all real.
所以就这样吧
So be it.
让这些怪物们自相残杀吧
Let the monsters kill each other.
当他们在北方打得你死我活的时候
And while they battle in the North,
我们就夺回原本属于我们的土地
we take back the lands that belong to us.
- 然后呢？ - 然后我们继续统治
- And then what? - And then we rule.
等北方的战事结束 某一方胜利了
When the fighting in the North is over, someone wins.
你明白这些 是吧？
You understand that, don't you?
如果死人赢了 他们会横扫南方 把我们全杀了
If the dead win, they march south and kill us all.
如果活人赢了 我们背叛过他们
If the living win, and we've betrayed them,
他们也会一路向南 把我们全杀了！
they march south and kill us all!
坦格利安家族和史塔克家族已经想把我们全灭
The Targaryens and the Starks already want to kill us all.
他们中的大部分会在北境死去
Most of them will die in the North.
我在战场上面对过他们
I faced them in the field.
我们没有机会 我们没法战胜龙
We can't beat them. We can't beat their dragons.
你看见了几条龙？
How many dragons did you see at the pit?
- 两条 - 那第三条怎么了？
- Two. - What happened to the third?
据我们所知 它在保护丹妮莉丝的舰队！
For all we know, it's guarding her fleet!
她带着她的龙 多斯拉克人和无垢者来到这里
She came here with her dragons and her Dothraki and her Unsullied.
她是来炫耀她的全部武力
She came here to show us all her power.
不对 一定是有事情发生 龙不是无敌的
No, something happened. The dragons are vulnerable.
我们打不过多斯拉克人 我们寡不敌众
We can't beat the Dothraki. We don't have the numbers.
没有任何家族支持我们！
We don't have the support of the other houses!
不 有更好的势力支持我们 我们有铁金库
No, we have something better. We have the Iron Bank.
父亲谈论黄金的重要性时 你真该多听听
You should've listened more when Father spoke about the importance of gold.
哦 那对你来说太无聊了 我懂
Oh, I know it's boring for you.
你只想打猎 骑马 战斗
You just wanted to hunt and ride and fight.
但是我听了 我学到了
But I listened, I learned.
高庭的黄金给我们带来了厄斯索斯最强劲的军队……
Highgarden bought us the most powerful army in Essos...
黄金团
the Golden Company.
应该有两万人 战马 还有战象
20,000 men, horses, elephants, I believe.
远水解不了近渴啊
The Golden Company is not here.
黄金团在厄斯索斯
They're in Essos.
身在厄斯索斯的佣兵团能怎么帮助我们？
How is a mercenary company in Essos going to help us?
你真的觉得攸伦·葛雷乔伊临阵脱逃
Do you really think Euron Greyjoy turned tail
驶回铁群岛了吗？
and sailed back to the Iron Islands?
你觉得他放弃了
Do you think he abandoned
迎娶女王的机会吗？
the chance to marry the queen?
没人会离我而去
No one walks away from me.
他正率舰队驶往厄斯索斯
He's sailing with his fleet to Essos.
他将载着黄金团而归
He's going to ferry the Golden Company back here
来帮助我们赢下战争 赢下维斯特洛
to help us win the war for Westeros.
你和攸伦·葛雷乔伊密谋了这件事 却没事先告诉我
You plotted with Euron Greyjoy without telling me,
我可是你军队的总司令啊
the commander of your armies?
而你和提利昂密谋了那次会面
And you conspired with Tyrion,
他可是我们的杀父仇人
the man who murdered our father,
你事先也没有告诉我——你的女王
without telling me, your queen.
我没和他密谋任何事
I didn't conspire with him.
你未经我同意秘密和他会面
You met with him in secret without my consent.
你计划着让我的敌人获益
You planned to promote my enemies' interests.
这就是阴谋的定义
That is the definition of conspiracy.
我承诺率军北上
I pledged to ride north.
我打算遵守诺言
I intend to honor that pledge.
- 而那将是叛国之举 - 叛国？
- And that will be treason. - Treason?
违背女王的命令 和她的敌人并肩作战
Disobeying your queen's command, fighting with her enemies.
你管这叫什么？
What would you call it?
我叫它什么都无所谓
Doesn't matter what I'd call it.
我告诉过你 没人能离我而去
I told you no one walks away from me.
你要让他杀了我？
Are you going to order him to kill me?
我是你唯一的亲人了
I'm the only one you have left.
我们的孩子死了 父亲也死了
Our children are gone, our father is gone.
现在只剩我和你了
It's just me and you now.
还有一个即将出世
There's one more yet to come.
那就下令吧
Give the order, then.
我不再相信你了
I don't believe you.
山姆威尔·塔利
学城学徒 蓝道·塔利的长子
吉莉
请进
Come in.
山姆威尔·塔利
Samwell Tarly.
我不确定你还能不能记住我
I wasn't sure if you'd remember me.
我能记住所有事
I remember everything.
你帮我们出了长城
You helped us get beyond the Wall.
- 你是个好人 - 噢 谢谢称赞
- You're a good man. - Oh, well, thank you,
但是 呃 我也不确定我是不是好人
but, um, I'm not sure that I am.
在塞外都发生了什么？
What happened to you beyond the Wall?
我成了三眼乌鸦
I became the Three-Eyed Raven.
喔！
Oh!
我不知道那是什么
I don't know what that means.
我能看到过去发生的事
I can see things that happened in the past.
也能看到正在发生的事
I can see things happening now
世界各地的事
all over the world.
你为什么来临冬城？
Why did you come to Winterfell?
呃……
Um...
琼恩是对抗死者一战的领袖
Jon's the one to lead the fight against the dead.
我知道
I know he is.
但是他一个人做不来
But he can't do it alone,
所以我来帮助他
so I've come here to help him.
他正在回临冬城的路上
He's on his way back to Winterfell
和丹妮莉丝·坦格利安一起
with Daenerys Targaryen.
你……你通过……
You... you saw this in...
某种视野？
in a vision?
哦
Oh.
他需要知道真相
He needs to know the truth.
什么真相？
The truth about what?
他自己的
About himself.
除了我 没有人知道
No one knows. No one but me.
琼恩并不是我父亲的儿子
Jon isn't really my father's son.
他是雷加·坦格利安和我姑姑莱安娜·史塔克的儿子
He's the son of Rhaegar Targaryen and my aunt, Lyanna Stark.
他在多恩的一座塔里出生
He was born in a tower in Dorne.
他其实并不姓雪诺
His last name isn't really Snow,
应该姓沙德
it's Sand.
不是的
It's not.
多恩的私生子都姓沙德
Dornish bastards are named Sand.
在学城 我抄了一个总主教的日记
At the Citadel, I transcribed a High Septon's diary.
他废除了雷加和伊莉亚的婚姻
He annulled Rhaegar's marriage to Elia.
然后他给雷加和莱安娜办了一场秘密婚礼
He wed Rhaegar and Lyanna in a secret ceremony.
你确定吗？
Are you certain?
总主教把这些写在了他的私人日记里
It's what the High Septon wrote in his private diary.
我觉得他没理由撒谎
I don't know why he'd lie.
你能看到这种事情吗？
Is this something you can see?
天父 铁匠 战士
Father, Smith, Warrior,
圣母 少女 老妪 陌客
Mother, Maiden, Crone, Stranger.
- 我属于她 她属于我…… - 我属于他 他属于我……
- I am hers and she is mine... - I am his and he is mine...
从今日起 直至永远
from this day until the end of my days.
劳勃的反叛建立在谎言之上
Robert's Rebellion was built on a lie.
雷加没有绑架或是强暴我姑姑
Rhaegar didn't kidnap my aunt or rape her.
他们彼此相爱
He loved her.
两情相悦
And she loved him.
而琼恩……
And Jon...
琼恩的真名……
Jon's real name...
他的名字是伊耿·坦格利安
His name is Aegon Targaryen.
你必须保护他
You have to protect him.
答应我 奈德
Promise me, Ned.
他从来都不是私生子
He's never been a bastard.
他是铁王座的继承人
He's the heir to the Iron Throne.
他需要知道这个消息
He needs to know.
我们得告诉他
We need to tell him.
你还好吗？
Are you all right?
只是感觉很奇怪
It's just strange.
我相信他爱着我 以他自己那可怕的方式
In his own horrible way, I believe he loved me.
你做了正确的事
You did the right thing.
是你做的
You did it.
我只是个刽子手
I'm just the executioner.
是你定的罪
You passed the sentence.
你才是临冬城公爵夫人
You're the Lady of Winterfell.
你对此很反感吗？
Does that bother you?
我不会成为一个像你一样好的公爵夫人
I was never going to be as good a lady as you.
所以我得另寻出路
So I had to be something else.
我不会在你经历过的事中存活下来
I never could have survived what you survived.
你会的
You would have.
你是我知道的最坚强的人
You're the strongest person I know.
我觉得这是你对我说过的最友善的话了
I believe that's the nicest thing you've ever said to me.
别以为这就是常态
Well, don't get used to it.
你还是很奇怪 很烦人
You're still very strange and annoying.
“凛冬之时 我们必须保护自己
"In winter, we must protect ourselves.
彼此照应”
Look after one another."
父亲说过的
Father.
“当大雪降下 冷风吹起
"When the snows fall and the white winds blow,
独行狼死
the lone wolf dies,
群聚狼生”
but the pack survives."
我想他了
I miss him.
我也是
Me, too.
托蒙德
“巨人克星”
贝里·唐德里恩
“闪电大王”
真高啊
It's a long way down.
是啊 乌鸦们一直说我会习惯的
Yeah. The crows keep telling me I'll get used to it.
我看到有动静……
I can see movement...
看 在林子的边缘！
Watch, on the tree line!
是什么？
What is it?
快啊！
Come on!
快跑！跑！
Run! Run!
衣柜字幕组出品
维基新站网址：http://asoiaf.huiji.wiki/
本集关键字：龙穴 黄金团 错误的春天
衣柜字幕组第七季人员巡礼 排名不分先后
翻译：熊岛莱安娜 叽拇啾 芹泽多摩熊 独胆空调 凯岩城的黑发狮子 Ashara_C Taffy的北境雪诺
耗斯特洛夫斯卡娅子 桔子爱吃大西瓜 黑特泽沃儿德 小明 小猴会聪明 適之 小愤青菜 42_Lily 点儿兔子
校对：北落师门 依依Eva 兮迩CeCe 临冬城的狮子 龙的命根子 波隆 艾莉娅的缝衣针 dhpike 守誓剑 托曼·兰尼斯特 小猴会聪明
后期：依依Eva Jeremy 肉喵 加文·维斯特林 嘥氣
总监：临冬城的狮子 北落师门     衣柜字幕组发起人：baozhenyuawabi
翻译：熊岛莱安娜 叽拇啾 芹泽多摩熊 独胆空调 凯岩城的黑发狮子 Ashara_C Taffy的北境雪诺
耗斯特洛夫斯卡娅子 桔子爱吃大西瓜 黑特泽沃儿德 小明 小猴会聪明 適之 小愤青菜 42_Lily 点儿兔子
校对：北落师门 依依Eva 兮迩CeCe 临冬城的狮子 龙的命根子 波隆 艾莉娅的缝衣针 dhpike 守誓剑 托曼·兰尼斯特 小猴会聪明
后期：依依Eva Jeremy 肉喵 加文·维斯特林 嘥氣
总监：临冬城的狮子 北落师门     衣柜字幕组发起人：baozhenyuawabi